Finding Aid for the Allied Architects Association of Los Angeles Records LSC.1257
UCLA Library Special Collections
Allied Architects Association of Los Angeles records
1921-1944
UCLA Library Special Collections
Allied Architects Association of Los Angeles
Architects Bureau, Ltd.
LSC.1257
12.5 linear feet (25 boxes)
The Allied Architects Association of Los Angeles, California was founded ca. 1921 to provide municipal, county, state, and national governments with professional architects at a reasonable cost. AAALA did not accept or perform architectural services for private individuals or firms. The collection consists of the Association's minutes, financial records, publications, clippings, photographs, and contracts. Also includes minutes and financial records of the Architects Bureau Limited, Los Angeles.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
PORTIONS OF THIS COLLECTION HAVE BEEN DIGITIZED. See the Existence and Location of Copies note for the link to the digitized materials.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Transferred from Architecture and Urban Planning Library.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942303123606533
Biography
The Allied Architects Association of Los Angeles, California was founded ca. 1921; its purpose was to "advance the art of architecture and by professional cooperation and collaboration to secure for and provide municipal, county, state, and national governments and organizations formed for civic betterment, or mutual or business advancement with the highest and best expression of the profession of architecture at the least possible cost..."; AAALA did not accept or perform architectural services for private individuals or firms.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of minutes, financial records, publications, clippings, photographs, and contracts related to the Allied Architects Association of Los Angeles (AAALA). Includes minute books (1921-36), scrapbooks of clippings about buildings, financial statements, photographs of preliminary sketches for various jobs including the Los Angeles Hall of Justice building, bulletins of the AAALA, and proceedings of the American Institute of Architects (1921-40). Also includes minutes and financial records of the Architects Bureau Limited, Los Angeles.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Minute books (Boxes 1-8).
Financial records (Boxes 9-10).
Projects (Boxes 11-20, 22).
Records of Architects Bureau Ltd. (Boxes 21-22).
Publications (Boxes 23-25).
Online Items Available
Portions of this collection have been digitized and are available online: Allied Architects Association of Los Angeles Records (3 items).
Clippings files.; Organization files.; Architecture -- California -- Los Angeles -- Societies, etc. -- Archives.; Allied Architects Association of Los Angeles--Archives; Architects Bureau, Ltd.--Archives.
- Minute books
  - vol.1-2, 1921-1922. (Box 1)
  - vol.3-5, 1923-May 1924. (Box 2)
  - vol.6-7, May-November 1924. (Box 3)
  - vol.8-9, November 1924-February 1925. (Box 4)
  - vol.10-12, February-November 1925. (Box 5)
  - vol.13-15, November 1925-July 1934. (Box 6)
  - vol.16-17, July 1934-March 1936. (Box 7)
    Scope and Contents note
    vol.16 includes report and accounts, December 1933.
  - Executive Committee, 1944.; 1 vol. (Box 7)
  - Investment Committee, 1944.; 1 vol. (Box 8)
  - Resolutions, 1921-1922.; 2 vol. (Box 8)
- Financial Records
  - Financial statements., 2 vol. (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous., 4 vol. (Box 10)
- Projects
  - Volume containing articles of incorporation, by-laws and service contracts. (Box 11)
  - Agreements and assignments relating to jobs., 1 vol. (Box 11)
  - Agreements and reports relating to jobs., 3 vol. (Box 12)
  - Studies for Los Angeles Hall of Justice building., 1 vol. (Box 13)
  - Photographs of preliminary sketches for various jobs., 2 vol. (Box 13)
  - Photographs of preliminary sketches for various jobs., 1 vol. (Box 14)
  - Photographs of jobs., 1 vol. (Box 14)
  - Photographs of buildings., 1 vol. (Box 15)
  - Scrapbook of clippings about buildings., 2 vol. (Box 15)
  - Scrapbook of clippings about buildings (Box 16, Box 17, Box 18, Box 19, Box 20)
  - Photographs and other reproductions of plans., 3 folders. (Box 22)
- Records of Architects Bureau, Limited
  - Minute books, 1931-1939.; 2 vol. (Box 21)
  - Financial records., 2 vol. (Box 22)
- Publications
  - Bulletins of the AAALA. (Box 23)
  - Proceedings of the American Institute of Architects, 1921-1940. (Box 24)
  - Visitors' book, 1925-1937. (Box 25)